Finding Aid for the Carey McWilliams Papers LSC.1319
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 2. Correspondence and research files, 1896-1982; 38 boxes
  - 2B. Files on subjects, 1914-1982; 20 boxes
    - Red-Baiting (2 of 2), 1936, 1953-1959; ca. 20 items. (Box 40, Folder 6)
      Newspaper clippings. Includes 2 copies of the journal Alert, and an article by McWilliams entitled, "The Writer and Civil Liberties" (The Open Forum).
    - Red-Baiting--Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1953-1958, 1977; 25 items. (Box 40, Folder 7)
      Correspondence, the television transcript of a broadcast by Tom Duggan, press releases, minutes, statement of principles, a program, and a clipping. McWilliams helped form this Committee.
    - Red-Baiting--Investigations (1 of 2), 1948-1954, 1957; 21 items. (Box 40, Folder 8)
      Correspondence (including 1 letter from Hubert H. Humphrey to Freda Kirchwey with an accompanying statement, 1 letter from Victor Rabinowitz with an accompanying memorandum, and 1 piece of correspondence with Guy Endore), typed notes, press releases, pamphlets, a newsletter, newspaper clippings, and the Sixth Report of the Senate Investigating Committee on Education. Some of these materials refer to McWilliams's purported communist ties.
    - Red-Baiting--Investigations (2 of 2), 1947-1956; ca. 50 items. (Box 40, Folder 9)
      Newspaper clippings, and printed materials concerning Lillian Tapley, Chairman of the Plymouth Meeting Library Committee, being subpoenaed by the Un-American Activities Committee.
    - Red-Baiting--Sacramento, 1963; 50 items. (Box 40, Folder 10)
      Correspondence (including with W. Colston Leigh, Inc.), signed contracts, a report, and newspaper clippings, most of which refer to protests over McWilliams's appearance in Sacramento.
    - Red-Baiting--The Tenney Committee, 1948-1954; 9 items. (Box 40, Folder 11)
      References to McWilliams that appeared in the Fourth Report of the California Senate Fact-Finding Committee on Un-American Activities accompanied by McWilliams's comments. Also includes a list of activities with which McWilliams was associated compiled by the committee and related materials.
    - Relevance (1 of 3), 1969-1973; 31 items. (Box 41, Folder 1)
      Newsletter, articles, and clippings. Subjects include the search for relevancy in higher education, politics, and religion. Includes McWilliams's article "In Quest of Relevance."
    - Relevance (2 of 3), 1969-1972; ca. 70 items. (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Relevance (3 of 3), 1969-1972; ca. 70 items. (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Scientology, 1976-1979; ca. 80 items. (Box 41, Folder 4)
      1 letter, typed notes, clippings, and photocopies of clippings.
    - Skokie, Illinois--Rights (1 of 3), 1976-1979; 13 items. (Box 41, Folder 5)
      Typed notes, a press release, articles, and clippings from The Nation. Also includes a signed note from Alice Greenfield McGrath.
    - Skokie, Illinois--Rights (2 of 3), 1977-1979; ca. 50 items. (Box 41, Folder 6)
      Newspaper clippings. Subjects include racism, book banning, free speech, Nazis, and the Ku Klux Klan.
    - Skokie, Illinois--Rights (3 of 3), 1977-1979; ca. 50 items. (Box 41, Folder 7)
      Newspaper clippings. Subjects include racism, free speech, Nazis, and the Ku Klux Klan.
    - Small Magazines (1 of 2), 1956-1965, 1974-1979; 34 items. (Box 41, Folder 8)
      1 letter to Morris Rubin, articles (including 6 by Theodore Peterson), and clippings.
    - Small Magazines (2 of 2), 1936, 1956-1957, 1971-1977; 19 items. (Box 41, Folder 9)
      Letters (including 1 from Bob Sherrill), handwritten notes, a leaflet, articles (2 by McWilliams: "The Nation and the Magazine of Opinion" and "A Frank Appraisal of the Press") and newspaper clippings.
    - Socialism (1 of 3), 1914, 1950-1980; 30 items. (Box 42, Folder 1)
      Typed notes, press releases, leaflets, articles, and clippings. Also contains a paper by Richard Platkin and Charles O'Connell entitled, "Does Dutt's Thesis Apply to the Contemporary U.S. Crisis?"
    - Socialism (2 of 3), 1976-1980; ca. 70 items. (Box 42, Folder 2)
      Newspaper clippings and reviews.
    - Socialism (3 of 3), 1964-1979; ca. 70 items. (Box 42, Folder 3)
      Newspaper clippings and reviews. Includes a copy of The Nation.
    - Southern California Newspapers, 1977-1979; 9 items. (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Spanish Speaking Minority (1 of 2), 1978-1980; 43 items. (Box 42, Folder 5)
      Correspondence with Dennis Laurence Cuddy and the Association of Mexican American Educators, letters, handwritten and typed notes, press releases, and clippings. Includes an untitled article by McWilliams about illegal aliens.
    - Spanish Speaking Minority (2 of 2), 1976-1980; 24 items. (Box 42, Folder 6)
      Newspaper clippings, and a Los Angeles Times pull-out about Mexico. Includes 2 McWilliams's articles ("Dope & Jobs: The Border Story" from The Nation, and a Second Thoughts column discussing the Immigration and Naturalization Services proposed fence between Mexico and the United States).
    - Synanon, 1978-1979; ca. 60 items. (Box 42, Folder 7)
      1 letter from Victor Navasky, 1 letter from Arthur H. Samuelson to Victor Navasky, articles, and clippings.
    - Tic Douloureux, 1966-1979; 21 items. (Box 42, Folder 8)
      Correspondence with doctors, clippings, and typed and handwritten notes documenting the occurrences and treatment of the painful facial twitch from which McWilliams suffered.
    - Two Americas, 1970-1975; 24 items. (Box 42, Folder 9)
      A press release, a newsletter, articles, and clippings.
    - Two-Party System (1 of 2), 1965-1966; 20 items. (Box 43, Folder 1)
      1 letter from Stuart Cuthbertson, newsletters, articles, clippings, and assorted printed materials. Also includes papers ("Technology and the Enterprise of Philosophy" by Emmanuel G. Mesthene, "Ideas in Action" by Stephen Horn, and "Social Cleavages in the 1964 Election" by Philip E. Converse).
    - Two-Party System (2 of 2), 1965-1966; ca. 40 items. (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Vietnam Aftermath (1 of 2), 1965-1978; 17 items. (Box 43, Folder 3)
      Letters from Frederick L. Schuman and Stephen G. Cary, handwritten note from Joseph H. Crown, a paper entitled "The Saga of the Lawyers Committee on American Policy Towards Vietnam" by Crown, a lecture entitled "Tragedy in Vietnam" by Schuman, handwritten and typed notes, lists of Nation articles about Vietnam, and clippings.
    - Vietnam Aftermath (2 of 2), 1966-1978; ca. 50 items. (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Violence and Television, 1975-1977; 34 items. (Box 43, Folder 5)
      Press releases, and clippings (mostly newspaper).
    - War on Poverty, 1963-1965; 4 items. (Box 43, Folder 6)
      A press release, a clipping, a copy of The Yale Law Journal, and a report for the California Welfare Study Commission by Earl Raab and Hugh Folk entitled, "Pattern of Dependent Poverty in LA."
    - Water, 1977-1979; ca. 50 items. (Box 43, Folder 7)
      1 press release, and clippings (mostly newspaper).
    - Zoot Suit--The Play, 1977-1979; 48 items. (Box 43, Folder 8)
      1 letter from Kenneth Brecher, 1 playbill, 1 copy of Westways, a newsletter, and clippings. Also includes an annotated copy of McWilliams's article for The Nation. The subjects are the play's production in Los Angeles and New York, and its author Luis Valdez.
    - Zoot Suit--Sleepy Lagoon, 1969, 1975-1979; 26 items. (Box 43, Folder 9)
      Correspondence with Ernest-Ulrich Franzen, handwritten and typed notes, a reading list about Mexicans in North America, a notebook from unidentified source, and newspaper clippings and photocopies. Subjects include the Zoot Suit riots, and the monograph Zoot Suit Murders by Thomas Sanchez.
    - 1920s, 1958-1976; 22 items. (Box 45, Folder 1)
      2 letters, handwritten and typed notes, articles, and clippings.
    - 1930s (1 of 3), 1938-1942, 1960-1976; 40 items. (Box 45, Folder 2)
      Manuscript about organized labor in Hollywood and the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees entitled, "Chapter I: The Eternal Triangle." Also includes typed and handwritten (19 leaves) notes, clippings, assorted printed materials, and a copy of the journal Working Papers for a New Society with an article by McWilliams: "California's Utopias."
    - 1930s (2 of 3), 1940, 1964-1974; 28 items. (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Typed notes (13 leaves), correspondence (including 2 long letters from Helen H.), transcript of an interview of McWilliams discussing the La Follette Committee, and a transcript of an interview with Fred Ross. Includes articles by McWilliams: "La Follette Hearings: Final Sessions," and "Civil Rights in California."
    - 1930s (3 of 3), 1934-1940, 1959-1975; 37 items. (Box 45, Folder 4)
      Articles, newspaper clippings, and photocopies. Includes the following McWilliams's articles: "Franco, Congress and the Pentagon," "Civil Rights in California," "The Joads on Strike," and "American Exiles."
    - 1940s, 1942-1949, 1969-1976; ca. 60 items. (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Typed and handwritten (9 leaves) notes, an outline entitled, "Community Action: Race Relations," clippings, and assorted printed materials. Also contains a report by the Institute of Ethnic Affairs--Division of Spanish Speaking People in the United States.
    - 1950s, 1951, 1959-1967, 1974-1975; ca. 50 items. (Box 45, Folder 6)
      Typed notes, clippings, a manuscript by McWilliams (Confidential Talk with Stevenson), and a newsletter with an article by McWilliams (McWilliams on Goslin). Subjects include plastic bag deaths, suicides, the Pasadena School Board, the Cal Tech Chinese scientist, and McCarthyism.
    - 1950s--The Vile Decade, 1951-1962, 1973; ca. 60 items. (Box 45, Folder 7)
      Correspondence, typed notes, newsletter, leaflets, clippings, the publication What Price Security by Ben H. Bagdikian, and a copy of the Monthly Review with an article by McWilliams entitled "Liberty in the Warfare State." The main subject is McCarthyism.
    - Acreage, 1977-1980; ca. 50 items. (Box 45, Folder 8)
      Correspondence, press release, clippings, and assorted printed materials. Subject is primarily farm size and water usage.
    - Affluence (1 of 2), 1964-1965; 25 items. (Box 46, Folder 1)
      Handwritten and typed notes, press release, newsletter, and article clippings. Includes an untitled report on economic challenges by Theodore J. Kreps, a paper entitled, "Ethics and the Social Relations of Science" by Barry Commoner, and McWilliams's article, "Ethics in an Affluent Society."
    - Affluence (2 of 2), 1962-1965; ca. 70 items. (Box 46, Folder 2)
      Newspaper clippings. Subjects include academic cheating, ethics in foreign policy, youth drug usage, and James B. Carey and the International Union of Electrical Workers.
    - Aging, 1971-1979; ca. 30 items. (Box 46, Folder 3)
      Public Affairs Pamphlet and clippings (mostly newspaper).
    - Agriculture, 1976-1980; ca. 40 items. (Box 46, Folder 4)
      Leaflet and clippings (mostly newspaper). Subjects include crops and farm land.
    - The American Crisis (1 of 2), 1953, 1966-1968; 35 items. (Box 46, Folder 5)
      Correspondence with Frank Pickstock, press releases, newsletters, articles, and clippings. Also includes a statement by The Southern Regional Council entitled "On The National Crisis," and a lecture by J. William Fulbright entitled "The Two Americas."
    - The American Crisis (2 of 2), 1962-1968; ca. 60 items. (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Architecture (1 of 2), 1930, 1945, 1972-1979; 16 items. (Box 46, Folder 7)
      Correspondence (including a letter mentioning Richard Neutra), photocopies of articles, and clippings. Primary subject is architecture in California.
    - Architecture (2 of 2), 1965, 1971-1980; ca. 40 items. (Box 46, Folder 8)
      Newspaper clippings. Primary subject is architecture in California.
    - Arms, 1975-1980; ca. 30 items. (Box 46, Folder 9)
      Press releases (2 items) and newspaper clippings. Subjects include military spending and public policies.
    - Arts and Crafts, 1932, 1976-1979; 10 items. (Box 46, Folder 10)
      Clippings about California arts and crafts.
    - The Bicentennial (1 of 3), 1969-1976; 36 items. (Box 47, Folder 1)
      Correspondence (with Jack Greene, Phyllis Belk, and McKinley C. Olson), an untitled manuscript by J.W. Gitt, handwritten and typed notes and quotations, newsletter, pamphlet, and clippings. Includes McWilliams's article "Thoughts on the Bicentennial" from The Nation.
    - The Bicentennial (2 of 3), 1969-1976; ca. 50 items. (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - The Bicentennial (3 of 3), 1969-1976; ca. 50 items. (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - The Blacklist (1 of 3), 1951-1957, 1971-1978; 36 items. (Box 47, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, including letters from Hildreth Graves, Dore Schary, Dudley Nichols, Philip Langner, John Caughey, Joseph Navarro, and Barbara Beecher. Also includes a typed note, a press release, a copy of the Hollywood Review, and a paper entitled, "Crossfire: A Dialectical Attack."
    - The Blacklist (2 of 3), 1948-1957, 1974-1980; 33 items. (Box 47, Folder 5)
      Press releases, a typed note, leaflets, articles, clippings, and assorted printed materials. Includes a photocopy of McWilliams's Nation article "Hollywood Gray List," as well as an ACLU publication "The Way We Really Were" (for the 183rd anniversary of the Bill of Rights), and the article "Legal Aspects of 'Political Black Listing' in the Entertainment Industry" by Harold W. Horowitz.
    - The Blacklist (3 of 3), 1948-1978; ca. 120 items. (Box 47, Folder 6)
      Photocopies of newspaper and magazine articles and the Congressional Record.
    - Blacks (1 of 4), 1953, 1960-1961, 1974-1979; 21 items. (Box 47, Folder 7)
      2 letters, a manuscript by Bruce Catton about the Civil War, note, press releases, 6 ACLU papers, a speech by Dr. W.E.B. DuBois, "The Wrongs which Suppress Our Rights," and lectures by Gunnar Myrdal entitled, "An American Dilemma Revisited." Also includes the pamphlet, "The Negro in American Life" distributed by the United States Information Service.
    - Blacks (2 of 4), 1965-1978; 14 items. (Box 47, Folder 8)
      Articles, clippings, a copy of The Nation that contains an article by McWilliams: "Halfway on the Long Walk." Subjects include race relations and prejudice.
    - Blacks (3 of 4), 1972-1979; ca. 40 items. (Box 48, Folder 1)
      Newspaper clippings. Subjects include civil rights, Eldridge Cleaver, segregation, and unemployment.
    - Blacks (4 of 4), 1974-1979; ca. 100 items. (Box 48, Folder 2)
      Newspaper clippings. Subjects include integration, discrimination, politics.
    - Book Material (1 of 5), 1957-1968; 52 items. (Box 48, Folder 3)
      Typewritten notes, quotations, and poems ("Encounter" by John Wain, "The Crossing," and "Russian Art Club Reverie..."). Also includes articles, book reviews, clippings, and an address by Leslie A. White entitled, "Man, Culture, and Human Beings." Topics include writers and literature.
    - Book Material (2 of 5), 1957-1960; ca. 50 items. (Box 48, Folder 4)
      Newspaper clippings and book reviews. Subjects include writers and literature.
    - Book Material (3 of 5), 1958, 1967-1968; 20 items. (Box 48, Folder 5)
      Articles, clippings, and book reviews. Subjects include writers and literature.
    - Book Material (4 of 5), 1963-1969; 21 items. (Box 48, Folder 6)
      A typed quotation, articles, clippings, and book reviews. Subjects include writers and literature.
    - Book Material (5 of 5), 1964-1966; ca. 60 items. (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Book Series for the Centennial, 1955-1966; 7 items. (Box 49, Folder 1)
      Correspondence with Stanley Moore, letters from Richard Sundt and Michael Blankfort, and a typewritten note regarding lists of influential books. Also contains literary reviews.
    - Books (1 of 2), 1930-1931, 1973, 1977-1979; 28 items. (Box 49, Folder 2)
      Typed notes on a program of the Southern California Library, a handwritten list of literary titles and prices, 2 letters (including 1 from McWilliams to John Fante), clippings, and a copy of the publication Don Ryan's Magazine.
    - Books (2 of 2), 1965, 1973-1980; ca. 70 items. (Box 49, Folder 3)
      Newspaper clippings and reviews. Subjects include publishing, writers, writing, and book sellers.
    - Brush Fires, 1979; 11 items. (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Business and Manufacture, 1979-1980; ca. 20 items. (Box 49, Folder 5)
      2 press releases, and clippings. Main subject is United States and Mexico economic ties.
    - California--Churches, 1976-1979; ca. 40 items. (Box 49, Folder 6)
      1 letter, and clippings (mostly newspaper). Main subject is religion in California.
    - California--Exceptionalism (1 of 3), 1959-1980; 15 items. (Box 49, Folder 7)
      3 letters, handwritten and typed notes, a manuscript (Has the Pacific Coast an Identifiable Culture by Otis Pease), an address by Jesse E. Hobson entitled, California Man in the 1980s, a transcript of an oral history interview of M. Larry Lawrence, and a study entitled, The Challenge of Leisure: A Southern California Case Study.
    - California--Exceptionalism (2 of 3), 1963-1975; 22 items. (Box 49, Folder 8)
      Clippings and printed publications.
    - California--Exceptionalism (3 of 3), 1964-1978; ca.60 items. (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - California--Growth, 1932, 1976-1979; 15 items. (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - California--Places, 1964-1979; 26 items. (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - California--Science and Technology, 1963-1979; 6 items. (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - California--Sociology, 1973-1979; ca. 30 items. (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - California--The Waning Dream (1 of 2), 1966-1975; 23 items. (Box 50, Folder 3)
      1 letter, 2 typewritten notes, articles, and clippings. Subjects include population shifts and sprawl.
    - California--The Waning Dream (2 of 2), 1963-1974; ca. 80 items. (Box 50, Folder 4)
      Newspaper clippings. Subjects include population shifts and sprawl.
    - Canadians, 1979; 11 items. (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Cars--Freeways, 1932, 1957, 1963, 1978-1979; ca. 30 items. (Box 50, Folder 6)
      Press release, article, and clippings (mostly newspaper).
    - Central Intelligence Agency (1 of 2), 1977-1980; 23 items. (Box 50, Folder 7)
      1 letter, typewritten note, press releases, articles, and clippings.
    - Central Intelligence Agency (2 of 2), 1976-1979; ca. 40 items. (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Chicago, 1967-1968; 2 items. (Box 50, Folder 9)
      A publication entitled, "Law & Disorder: The Chicago Convention and its Aftermath," and a report to the citizens of Chicago on the April 27 Peace Parade entitled, "Dissent and Disorder."
    - Chicanos, 1979; ca.40 items. (Box 50, Folder 10)
      Typewritten notes, and clippings (mostly newspaper).
    - China, 1979; 4 items. (Box 50, Folder 11)
      Newspaper clippings. Subjects are ports and trade.
    - Civil Liberties, 1978-1979; ca. 40 items. (Box 50, Folder 12)
      Typewritten note, press releases, newspaper clippings, Arms Control Today newsletter, and pamphlet on the proposed FBI charter.
    - The Cold War (1 of 2), 1976-1979; 27 items. (Box 65, Folder 1)
      Handwritten and typed notes and quotations, press releases, and 1 letter. This material was possibly compiled for a chapter in The Education of Carey McWilliams.
    - The Cold War (2 of 2), 1958-1976; 28 items. (Box 65, Folder 2)
      Articles and clippings. Also includes the published introduction by McWilliams to the reprint edition of The Education of Carey McWilliams, a photocopy of "The Watergate Putsch" by Seymour Melman, and a photocopy of "The American Left and the Dilemmas of the Cold War" by Joseph R. Starobin. This material was possibly compiled for a chapter in The Education of Carey McWilliams.
    - Collier's Magazine, 1951; 11 items. (Box 65, Folder 3)
      Correspondence, manuscript entitled "Helpless Drift," and clippings. Main subject is D.F. Fleming's article "Collier's wins World War III" that appeared in The Nation. Includes a copy of the article, a letter from Fleming, and a letter from the editors of Colliers.
    - Colorado (1 of 5), 1959-1976; 30 items. (Box 65, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, handwritten and typed notes. Includes letters from Casley Williams, George Killion, John Rolfe Burroughs, Marcellus M. Murdock, and others.
    - Colorado (2 of 5), 1922-1927, 1950, 1959, 1967-1976; 17 items. (Box 65, Folder 5)
      Articles, clippings, and a copy of The Steamboat Pilot.
    - Colorado (3 of 5), 1948-1949; ca. 40 items. (Box 65, Folder 6)
      Clippings, primarily from the Rocky Mountain Empire Magazine.
    - Colorado (4 of 5), 1930-1932, 1959, 1967-1975; ca. 50 items. (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Colorado (5 of 5), 1960-1976; 12 items. (Box 65, Folder 8)
      Brochures and leaflets.
    - Consensus Politics, 1965-1967; ca. 50 items. (Box 65, Folder 9)
      Clippings (mostly newspaper), a copy of the publication Commentary, and a pamphlet entitled, Alternative Perspectives on Vietnam.
    - Conservatism (1 of 3), 1955-1962; 6 items. (Box 69, Folder 1)
      2 letters, typewritten note, press release, text of speech by Raymond Loewy before the Society of Automobile Engineers, and text of an address by Harold Taylor entitled, Liberalism and the Modern World.
    - Conservatism (2 of 3), 1958-1967; ca. 70 items. (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Conservatism (3 of 3), 1957-1966; 25 items. (Box 69, Folder 3)
      Newsletters, articles, clippings, and the monograph Utopianism and Politics by J.L. Talmon.
    - Counter-Culture Culture, 1973-1975; ca. 60 items. (Box 69, Folder 4)
      Correspondence with Margaret Levi, David Gold, and Alan Wolfe. Also includes outlines/proposals for a book, and clippings.
    - Cults, 1969, 1976-1980; ca. 30 items. (Box 69, Folder 5)
      Press releases and clippings (mostly newspaper)
    - Deserts, 1971-1980; 16 items. (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Earthquakes, 1969-1979; ca. 60 items. (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - East Coast, 1972-1979; ca. 30 items. (Box 69, Folder 8)
      Clippings (mostly newspaper). Subjects include Hispanic immigrants, Puerto Rico, and illegal aliens in New York.
    - Eastern Europe, 1966-68, 1973; 71 items. (Box 69, Folder 9)
      Correspondence (with George Wheeler, Igor Hajek, and others), handwritten and typed notes and contact information, business cards, McWilliams's work schedule, and clippings. McWilliams traveled to Eastern Europe in July of 1967.
    - Ecology, 1977-1979; ca. 30 items. (Box 72, Folder 1)
      Press releases and clippings (mostly newspaper). Subjects include urban development, smog, flood control, and acid rain.
    - Economics, 1974-1979; ca. 20 items. (Box 72, Folder 2)
      Press releases, clippings (mostly newspaper), newsletter, pamphlet, and a report. Subjects include Pacific Rim trade, and industries and housing in Los Angeles.
    - Education, 1979-1980; ca. 20 items. (Box 72, Folder 3)
      Newspaper clippings. Subject include bilingual education and Spanish-speakers in the United States.
    - Ethics, ca. 1969-1971; ca. 40 items. (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Ethnics (1 of 3), 1966-1975; 28 items. (Box 72, Folder 5)
      Letters, press releases, articles, clippings, assorted printed materials, and a summary report from The National Consultation on Ethnic America. Also includes a dialogue discussion paper from the Conference on Ethnicity and Historical Consciousness or Identity in the Modern World; a paper for the American Educational Research Association by R.J. Havighurst entitled, "Cultural Pluralism and Education;" and a paper by Nathan Irvin Huggins entitled, "The Afro-American, National Character, and Community: Toward a new Synthesis."
    - Ethnics (2 of 3), 1972-1978; ca. 50 items. (Box 72, Folder 6)
      Clippings (mostly newspaper). Subjects include voting, different ethnic groups in the United States, affirmative action, and minorities.